[Music]
[音乐]
right thank you very much for coming to
对，非常感谢您的光临
the last session of this spring i/o
这个 Spring 的最后一堂课
which is an amazing conference and today
今天是一个了不起的会议
I'm going to speak about zero downtime
我将谈论零停机时间
deployment in Microsoft micro-services
Microsoft微服务中的部署
era and more specifically when you are
时代，更具体地说，当你
start using service meshes and yeah I
开始使用服务网格，是的，我
mean the examples are running in with a
表示示例正在运行
spring or a spring boot but of course I
Spring 或 spring boot ，但我当然
mean it it's the same thing can be
意味着它可以是同一件事
applied to any other technology even non
适用于其他任何技术
Java technology my name is Alex OTA
Java技术，我叫Alex OTA
walking rehab I'm the creator of a lot
康复康复我是很多人的创造者
of the towers and if you like this logo
塔楼，如果您喜欢这个徽标
which is Duke I mean this is Wizard Duke
这是公爵，我的意思是这是巫师公爵
I have some stickers after the session
会议结束后我有一些贴纸
if you want you can take some of them
如果您愿意，可以带一些
also I'm the co-author of testing Java
我也是测试Java的合著者
micro services and there is a raffle of
微服务，还有一个抽奖活动
one electronic book so if you follow me
一本电子书，所以如果您跟随我
on Twitter with a picture of the session
在Twitter上带有会议图片
you mentioned me in with a hashtag
你用话题标签提到我
spring ayo then I will you know raffle
Spring 的yo，那么我会知道抽奖吗
discount and a discount count of 100
折扣和折扣计数为100
percent of the electronic book so you
电子书的百分比，因此您
can go to many calm and then you just
可以变得很多冷静，然后你就
remove and download at the book if there
删除并下载该书（如果有）
is any question just please stop me and
有什么问题请阻止我，
said I have a question and I will answer
说我有一个问题，我会回答
it on the context you know I mean that
在上下文中，您知道我的意思是
at the end probably we will have some
最后，我们可能会有一些
time but if not I mean that you can do
时间，但如果不是，我是说你可以做到
it in at any time it's not a problem so
它在任何时候都没问题，所以
let us start probably some years ago I
让我们大概在几年前开始
mean that now it seems ages we develop
意味着现在看来我们发展了很多年
something like this it was like you know
这样的事情就像你知道的
a big monolith application where
一个大型的整体应用程序
everything was you know inside in fact
实际上你知道的一切
it was something like this I mean that
就是这样
we have some modules inside component
我们在组件内部有一些模块
all the application and even inside each
所有的应用程序，甚至每个内部
module we could have some you know some
模块我们可以有一些你知道一些
components and if you think about these
组件，如果您考虑这些
architecture you see that this is really
体系结构，您会看到这确实是
easy to deploy right you have like I
容易部署，就像我一样
don't know I mean that a word file or a
不知道我是说一个字文件还是一个
jar file it doesn't matter but it was a
jar文件无关紧要，但这是一个
big application where you just run it
大型应用程序，您可以在其中运行
and it works
它有效
the good thing is that usually with the
好处是通常
monolith you didn't deploy several times
你没有部署几次的整体
per day but you deploy it maybe once per
每天，但您可能每个月部署一次
month well probably if some of you said
一个月可能很好，如果你们中的一些人说
one per month it was like one every six
每月一次，就像每六个一次
months okay right one every six months
可以，每六个月一次
but it was really easy right because you
但这真的很容易，因为你
could even wait until 1:00 a.m. and at
甚至可以等到凌晨1:00
1:00 a.m. you just send a maintenance
凌晨1:00您只需要发送维护
page you swap duplication and that's all
页面交换重复，仅此而已
the deployment is done almost zero zone
部署几乎完成了零区域
time deployment the problem is that two
时间部署的问题是两个
years back we start thinking about
几年前，我们开始思考
breaking this monolith application to
打破这个整体应用程序
something like this we start with micro
像这样的东西，我们从微开始
services right and then we have
服务正确，然后我们有
something like this all these modules
像这样的东西，所有这些模块
all these components are spread across a
所有这些组成部分分布在
mesh all of them interconnected by
网格所有它们相互连接
network and as you can see this is a
网络，如您所见，这是一个
graph structure it's not a tree it's a
图结构不是树，而是树
graph where all the services can be
可以在其中显示所有服务的图
interconnected between them so it's
他们之间相互联系，所以
really quite interesting even some of
真的很有趣，甚至有些
the services might have a database and
服务可能有一个数据库，
each of the service has their own
每个服务都有自己的
database and even multiple points of
数据库甚至多个点
entry some services might have access to
某些服务可能有权访问的条目
the external wall and yet for this
外墙，但为此
reason it's a good idea to have always
总是拥有一个好主意
have an AP gateway in front to just
在前面有一个AP网关
support this use case the problem is
支持这个用例的问题是
that usually microservices I deployed
通常我部署的微服务
independently with monolith you just
与整体独立，你只是
have all or nothing but you may with
一无所有，但您可能拥有
micro services you might decide to
您可能决定选择的微服务
deploy a new version of one of these
部署其中之一的新版本
service multiple times per day so as you
每天为您服务多次
can see now the problem of downtime it's
现在可以看到停机时间的问题
quite more interesting because what's
比较有趣，因为
happen if there is downtime in this
如果有停机时间会发生
service maybe because we are updating
服务可能是因为我们正在更新
this service the thing is that there is
这项服务的事是
a cascade of errors so there is a lot of
一连串的错误，所以有很多
failures basically all the transitive
失败基本上都是可传递的
services that are depending to the
服务取决于
service are failing as well so now zero
服务也失败了，所以现在为零
downtime deployment is really important
停机部署非常重要
but the first thing that we need to
但是我们需要做的第一件事
think about
想一想
it how we do zero downtime deployments
它如何实现零停机时间部署
is that now deploy it's different and
是因为现在部署有所不同，
release and they're very important in
发布，它们在
the past in the monolith applications we
在整体应用中的过去
usually said I'm going to deploy the
通常说我要部署
application which basically means take
基本上意味着采取的申请
this application then put it on
然后将该应用程序放在
production and let's say that it was
生产，让我们说这是
equal saying deploy or release but with
平等地说部署或发布，但
micro services this has changed now one
微服务现在已经改变了
thing is deploy a service which means
事情是部署服务，这意味着
putting inside the production cluster
放入生产集群
and another thing is saying release the
另一件事是说释放
service which means start sending some
服务，这意味着开始发送一些
traffic to this service so this is
该服务的流量，所以这是
really important to start doing zero
从零开始真的很重要
downtime deployments in the micro
微型停机时间部署
services zebra there are several
服务斑马有几种
techniques I'm going to explain the
我将要解释的技术
common ones we're going to see also
常见的，我们还将看到
somewhat demos so you can get it a year
有点演示，所以你可以得到一年
now this one is blue green deployments
现在这是蓝绿色的部署
probably most of you knows what is blue
也许你们大多数人都知道蓝色是什么
green deployments just as a reminder
提醒您绿色部署
mining that we've got all our traffic
挖掘我们拥有的所有流量
that are going to the blue and bjurman
即将走向蓝色和比尤曼
and then we've got a build which is a
然后我们有一个构建
new version of my service so was it like
服务的新版本，就像
put it on production so this means that
投入生产，这意味着
I'm deploying to production and then I'm
我要部署到生产中，然后
releasing which basically means changing
释放基本上意味着改变
the routing from the blue to the green
从蓝色到绿色的路线
and we do not under ploy the blue W is
而且我们不采用蓝色W
still there and the reason that it's
仍然在那里，原因是
still there is because when you are
仍然存在是因为当你在
doing this change you can start
做这个改变，你可以开始
monitoring this service maybe you're
监视此服务也许您正在
using promises then you just check
使用诺言，然后您只需检查
primitives and if everything goes as
原语，如果一切顺利
expected then you leave this route but
预计，那么您离开这条路线，但是
if there is an error you can just really
如果有错误，您可以真正地
quickly change from green to blue and
快速从绿色变为蓝色，然后
that's a way is it an eek but it has one
那是一种方式，但是它有一个
big problem and the problem is that all
最大的问题是所有
your clients are affected if there is a
如果您的客户受到影响，
failure so if you are in created a new
失败，所以如果您正在创建一个新
version of your service you deploy it
您部署它的服务版本
you release it and then oh and there is
你释放它，然后哦，还有
a really big error then all your clients
一个非常大的错误，那么所有的客户
will start getting this error for any
将开始为任何得到此错误
reason what was created was that
原因是
canary release probably most of you
金丝雀释放可能你们大多数人
already knows cannot release which
已经知道不能释放哪个
basically comes from the the coal mines
基本上来自煤矿
right that I mean that in the past in
对，我是说过去
the coal mine there was some position
煤矿有一些位置
gases and there was no way to detect
气体，无法检测
this position gases so basically what
这个位置气体基本上是什么
the miners did was just taking a bird
矿工们只是在抓鸟
and go inside the mine with the bird and
和鸟一起进入矿井
good thing for the humans but not for
对人类有益，但对人类不利
the birds
那些鸟儿
is that the bird dies after 30 seconds
是那只鸟在30秒后死亡
of getting these poison gases I mean
这些毒气的意思是
while the humans it just takes two
而人类只需要两个
minutes so it means that the miners when
分钟，这意味着矿工在
they so that the bird was diet it means
他们让小鸟节食，这意味着
that they had one minute and a half to
他们有一分半钟的时间
just go out from the mining and this is
刚从采矿出去，这是
exactly what we're going to do not with
正是我们将要做的
the cannery because yeah I mean that we
罐头厂，因为是的，我是说我们
are software engineers but with software
是软件工程师，但拥有软件
so we've got all our blue bjurman I mean
所以我们有所有的蓝色bjurman
that this doesn't matter I mean that we
没关系，我的意思是我们
have our service the old service version
使用旧版本的服务
all the traffic goes through there we
所有的交通都经过那里
have this ball yellow ballad which is
有这个黄色的民谣
the new version and then we put this new
新版本，然后我们把这个新
version inside the old version and we
版本内的旧版本，我们
start standing for example the ten
开始站立，例如十
percent of the traffic so you send the
流量的百分比，以便您发送
ten percent of the traffic if everything
如果一切都占流量的百分之十
works as expected
按预期工作
we can increase and if not we can just
我们可以增加，否则我们就可以
remove this new version so you've got
删除此新版本，以便您
the ten percent if it works
如果有效的话，百分之十
twenty-five fifty percent seventy five
百分之二十五百分之七十五
percent and finally 100 percent so in
％，最后是100％
this way we are not affecting all the
这样我们不会影响所有的
users but just on a small portion of the
用户，但只占一小部分
users again these have another big
用户再次有另一个大
problem is that if you don't have a lot
问题是，如果你没有很多
of users per second that would be fine
每秒的用户数
but what's happen if you are Facebook
但是如果您是Facebook会发生什么
ten percent of your users are really big
百分之十的用户确实很大
amount of users that you are affecting
您影响的用户数量
with a possible problem
有可能的问题
so basically Google and Facebook has
所以基本上Google和Facebook都有
started doing one kind of techniques
开始做一种技术
this is an umbrella thing is called the
这是一把雨伞，叫做
lunches which basically dark lunches is
午餐基本上是深色午餐
a set of techniques that to
一套技术
on production without the end-user not
在没有最终用户的情况下生产
seeing it that you are using their own
看到你正在使用自己的
traffic to test your mill version and
交通测试您的工厂版本和
there are several techniques usually for
通常有几种技术
example Facebook uses one thing which is
例如Facebook使用的一件事是
called a arc
叫做弧
canneries which is something similar
罐头厂是类似的东西
like Connor Alice's but instead of doing
像康纳·爱丽丝（Connor Alice）一样，
using the percentage of traffic they are
使用他们的流量百分比
using for example range of IPs so if you
例如使用IP范围
are an employee of Facebook you're
是Facebook的员工
accessing Facebook from a certain range
从一定范围访问Facebook
of IPs basically the facebook offices so
IP基本上是Facebook办事处，所以
then you can get this IPS and said okay
那么你可以得到这个IPS并说好
I know that this is a user of Facebook
我知道这是Facebook用户
and it's an employee of Facebook so I'm
是Facebook的员工，所以我
going to send the traffic to the new
要将流量发送到新
version of Facebook in this way they are
这样的Facebook版本
going to test what's happening before I
在我之前要测试发生了什么
release this new version to all my users
向所有用户发布此新版本
this is called their kennels but in this
这叫做他们的狗窝
[Music]
[音乐]
one of the techniques that I use because
我使用的一种技术，因为
it's really easy is mirroring traffic
镜像流量真的很容易
and mirroring traffic is something like
镜像流量就像
that I'm just getting my two versions
我只有两个版本
deployed the old one and the new one and
部署了旧的和新的
I'm just sending a request then this
我只是发送一个请求，然后这个
request is sent to both of the services
请求被发送到两个服务
the blue and the green but notice here
蓝色和绿色，但请注意这里
that the blue has a double arrow
蓝色有一个双箭头
meanwhile the green is just and a single
同时绿色是唯一的
arrow the reason is that what really
箭头的原因是，真的
important from the point of view of user
从用户的角度来看很重要
is the old one so the user receives the
是旧的，因此用户会收到
response from the old one under new one
旧的回应新的回应
it just creates a fire-and-forget
它只是一劳永逸
request it sends a request and if they
请求它发送一个请求，如果他们
don't care about the response and this
不在乎回应和这个
is a really interesting technique
是一个非常有趣的技术
because it allows you to start
因为它可以让你开始
monitoring your new service we thought
监控我们认为的新服务
you know checking into these errors or
您知道检查这些错误或
not how it's performing without changing
而不改变它的表现
how your new users perceives that you
您的新用户如何看待您
have updated something
更新了一些东西
this might seems really complicated to
这似乎真的很复杂
do but if you are just using cuban areas
可以，但是如果您只是在使用古巴地区
which is let the factor platform for
这就是因素平台
micro-services then it's really yes it
微服务，那是真的
basically is easy because with
基本上很容易，因为
microservices we need to implement all
我们需要实现所有微服务
these cross-cutting concerns which is
这些跨领域的关注是
like you need to have an API you need to
就像您需要一个API一样
find a way to discover services to
找到一种发现服务的方式
invoke add services the last a CT the
最后一个CT调用添加服务
reservoir the pipeline of indication
储存指示管道
login monitoring and tracing all these
登录监视和跟踪所有这些
cross-cutting concerns are inherently
横切关注点本质上是
inside a micro service architecture and
在微服务架构中
this means that I can use basically all
这意味着我基本上可以使用所有
this discovery an invocation thing to
这个发现是一个调用的东西
define where I want to send the traffic
定义我要发送流量的位置
so with micro services it's really easy
因此使用微服务真的很容易
to do what really happen but is
去做真正发生的事情，但是
something like this that you start with
像这样的东西，你开始
micro services and you say ok I need to
微服务，你说好，我需要
do some kind of discovery I need to do
做一些我需要做的发现
some kind of tracing I need circuit
我需要某种追踪
breakers because there is a network
断路器，因为有网络
probably all of you that are in micro
也许你们所有人都在微
services already faced this problem and
服务已经面临这个问题，并且
you are ended by something having
你被某件事所结束
something like this you've got a
这样的事情你有一个
container the JVM and then you have a
容器JVM，然后您有一个
service and then you have the discovery
服务，然后您就会发现
part the scary part is where to send the
令人恐惧的部分是发送到哪里
traffic and then a load balancer a
流量，然后是负载均衡器
resiliency a matrix and tracing and all
弹性矩阵和跟踪以及所有
this logic is inside your service the
这个逻辑在您的服务内部
type of cool example is hystrix if you
如果您喜欢的话，很酷的示例类型是hystrix
got districts you just take your service
有地区，您只需服务
add a new dependency you annotate your
添加一个新的依赖项，您注释您的
service with something and then you've
服务，然后你已经
got circuit breaker behavior there
那里有断路器行为
notice that what you are really doing is
注意，您真正在做的是
just taking your service with all your
只为您全力以赴
business logic and just having some
业务逻辑，只是有一些
futures that comes from the
来自的期货
infrastructure like saying doing Tamati
像说做塔玛蒂的基础设施
retries or discovering other services
重试或发现其他服务
but what's happen if I told you that you
但是如果我告诉你你会怎样
can take all these cross-cutting
可以把所有这些交叉
concerns like discovery circuit breaker
发现断路器等问题
security all of these things and put it
安全所有这些东西，并把它
inside the infrastructure so you grab
在基础架构中，这样您就可以抓住
out from your service and you are just
从您的服务中出来，您就是
and impressed at or later and this is
并在或以后留下深刻的印象，这是
exactly what Easter is doing is this a
复活节到底在做什么
service match and a service match is a
服务匹配，服务匹配是
dedicated infrastructure layer for
专用的基础架构层
making service to service communication
服务到服务的沟通
safe fast unreliable so if you are into
安全快速不可靠，所以如果您喜欢
micro services wall and with sto you are
微服务墙，与您同在
getting something like this you've got a
得到这样的东西，你有一个
pot and then in this pot you've got a
锅，然后在这个锅里，你有一个
container and the cotton look of the JVM
容器和JVM的纯棉外观
and then you have your service but
然后你有你的服务，但
notice that now there is no logic
注意，现在没有逻辑
referring discovery nothing related to
指与发现无关的发现
circuit breakers security nothing but
断路器安全无非
we've got a sidecar container this is
我们有一个杂物箱，这是
another containers and now our pot have
另一个容器，现在我们的锅有
two containers my service and all this
两个容器，我的服务以及所有这些
logic and all this logic related to
逻辑以及与之相关的所有逻辑
infrastructure is just inside this
基础设施就在里面
container so I can reuse in all the
容器，这样我就可以在所有
services without having to do copy-paste
服务，而不必执行复制粘贴
and we want to be in details basically
我们希望基本上是细节
in case of istria inside of this sidecut
如果在此边角内有istria
container there is a name by proxy named
容器中有一个由代理命名的名称
a proxy it's like Ingenix or a chai
代理，就像Ingenix或chai
proxy which basically takes the requests
基本上接受请求的代理
and then manipulate this request to were
然后操纵此请求
sending the traffic to another place or
将交通发送到另一个地方或
doing automatic retrace or managing the
执行自动回溯或管理
certificate so what you can do with Sto
证书，以便您可以使用Sto做
the first thing is that you can do
第一件事是你可以做
traffic management you can start doing
您可以开始进行流量管理
things like I want to send all the
像我想发送所有的东西
traffic to service v1 and then you just
服务v1的流量，然后您就
execute a common and then other traffic
执行普通流量，然后执行其他流量
goes to service B - or I can say I want
去服务B-或者我可以说我想要
to send 90% of the traffic to service v1
将90％的流量发送到服务v1
and 90% of the traffic to the service
和90％的服务流量
version - so it's really easy to do with
版本-使用起来真的很容易
this - also it allows you to do
这-它也可以让你做
mirroring traffic's this is what we've
反映流量，这就是我们所要做的
seen of dark lunches you can send to
可以看到您可以发送的深色午餐
request to the - to services I mean that
请求-服务是我的意思是
it's one service but different versions
这是一项服务，但版本不同
you can also do dark canneries
你也可以做深色罐头厂
so you can start doing things like I
这样你就可以开始做像我这样的事情
want to send traffic that comes from
想要发送来自
chrome to this service and if it comes
铬这项服务，如果它来了
from a mobile to this other service and
从手机到其他服务，以及
if it comes from this user to this other
如果它来自此用户
service so
服务如此
easy to implement some kind of logics
易于实现某种逻辑
depending on who is connecting to your
取决于谁连接到您
application up so it implements secret
应用程序，使其实现秘密
breakers I mean that this is not for I
断路器，我的意思是这不适合我
mean this helps in case of long time
这意味着在长时间的情况下有帮助
deployments that are not really really
并非真的
zi long time deployments because it
子长时间部署，因为它
allows you to implement some kind of
允许您实施某种
automatic retries and pool ejection this
自动重试和池弹出
means that if I'm deploying a new
表示如果我要部署新的
service and then I start releasing and
服务，然后我开始发布
there is some period of time seconds
有一段时间秒
that this new service is not available
该新服务不可用
you can do some kind of retrace which
你可以做某种回溯
makes East you retrying any failure to a
让东您重试任何失败
spot that it's up and running and it's
当它启动并运行时
behaving correctly so this means that if
行为正确，所以这意味着
you have some downtime in the middle for
你在中间有一些停机时间
one two three seconds East you will get
一两三秒，你会得到东
the response of the failing service and
服务失败的响应和
reroute to the new service also sto
重新路由到新服务也
helps you on in cows engineering cows
帮助您继续努力
testing so if you want to do some kind
测试，所以如果你想做某种
of a cows testing of what's happening
母牛正在发生的事情的测试
inside my services when there are some
在我的服务中，当有一些
delays or there are some timeouts you
延迟或您超时
can use issue to simulate this just one
可以使用问题来模拟这一点
note about cows engineering I've talked
关于我谈论过的奶牛工程的说明
with several companies and all of them
与几家公司一起
tell me yeah we are using cousin Jeanine
告诉我，是的，我们正在使用堂兄珍妮
cows testing and and then I asked and
母牛测试，然后我问和
how it's going and now most of them tell
情况如何，现在大多数人都告诉
me wow it's a disaster right and I said
我哇这是一场灾难吧，我说
and while you're using while you're
而当你在使用时
studying doing cows engineering and the
学习做奶牛工程和
answer is because Netflix does it's
答案是因为Netflix做到了
really fun right because probably your
真的很有趣，因为您可能
problems are not the same as Netflix and
问题与Netflix和
probably you don't have the
可能您没有
infrastructure that Netflix have but in
Netflix拥有的基础设施
any case one of the most common problems
任何情况下最常见的问题之一
that they told me they have is that
他们告诉我他们有
there are some kind of emergencies in
有一些紧急情况
the sense that some developer decided
一些开发人员决定的感觉
it's a good time at 1:00 p.m. to do some
现在是下午1:00做某事的好时机
cows engineering and they start doing
牛工程，他们开始做
their own cows testing and the
他们自己的奶牛测试和
monitoring team
监察组
I start seeing some kind of random
我开始看到某种随机的
errors on the services and they say well
服务上的错误，他们说得很好
what's happening here and it's like we
这里发生了什么，就像我们
are doing some cows testing the thing is
正在做一些母牛测试的事情是
that nobody has notified to the
没有人通知
monitoring team that these tests are
监控团队，这些测试是
going to happen right so when you are
将会发生，所以当你
going to do cows engineering first of
首先要做牛工程
all
所有
teach yourself very well and second one
很好地教自己第二个
communicate to everyone that you're
与每个人交流你
going to do it because if not you won't
去做，因为如果没有的话，你不会
fight from some heartbreaks during the
在
test also the implements security and
还测试工具的安全性和
this is one of the reasons why most of
这是为什么大多数
the Red Hat users or customers are
红帽用户或客户是
interested in Istria and this is because
对Istria感兴趣，这是因为
sto allows you to communicate using MPLS
sto允许您使用MPLS进行通信
but under the covers you as a developer
但是作为开发人员的你
just just write things with HTTP and
只是用HTTP写东西，
then since you have this site container
然后，因为您拥有此网站容器
which receives all the traffic then you
接收所有流量，然后您
send a request to this sidecar container
向此小车容器发送请求
the second side car container transform
二次侧汽车集装箱改造
your HTTP request to HTTP request it
您的HTTP请求到HTTP请求
does the communication to the other
与对方沟通
service with the HTTP to the other my
与HTTP服务到其他我的
proxy this my proxy just transforms the
代理这我的代理只是转换
HTTP to HTTPS
HTTP到HTTPS
reaches the service so if you see that
到达服务，所以如果您看到
from the point of view of developers you
从开发者的角度来看
don't need to take care of managing
不需要照顾
certificates CAS revoking certificates
证书CAS吊销证书
and so on because from the point of view
等等，因为从角度来看
of developers everything is HTTP and
开发人员的一切都是HTTP和
implements absorbability which means
实现吸收性，这意味着
that it has by default with Prometheus
Prometheus默认具有的
and jigger to check what's happening
和跳汰机检查正在发生的事情
inside the mesh so now let's see all the
在网格内部，现在让我们来看所有
demos if you have gone or you have seen
演示，如果您走了或者您已经看过
other thoughts about zero don't and
关于零的其他想法不
deployments all people do exactly the
部署，所有人都可以做到
same thing which is like a hello all
一样的东西，大家好
services which is a stateless services
服务是无状态的服务
that you know you have one service and
您知道自己有一项服务，并且
then you send all the traffic to service
然后您将所有流量发送给服务
b1 and then they they show you that you
b1然后他们向您显示您
can do a canary sending the traffic to
可以做一个金丝雀将流量发送到
service b2 and yes of course it works
服务b2，当然可以
and it works because it's stainless but
它之所以有效是因为它不锈但是
I want to show you here is what's
我想告诉你这是什么
happened when there is a stateful
有状态的时候发生
services then it's quite more
服务，那就更多了
interesting right a morning more even
一个有趣的早晨
more interesting is when you start
更有趣的是，当您开始
changing the schema of the database so
更改数据库的架构，以便
I'm going to start this off first of all
我首先要开始
with the ephemeral state and a female
短暂的状态和一个女性
real estate our persistence that it's
房地产我们的坚持是
not a femur basically the example is the
基本上不是股骨，例子是
shopping cart right the shopping cart is
正确的购物车是
something that it's persisted somehow
它以某种方式持续存在的东西
but it's ephemeral if the session goes
但是如果会议进行得很短暂
down you loss so have done this in the
降低您的损失，所以在
past well basically I did something like
过去基本上我做了类似的事情
this I have my Reuter and then I have my
我有我的路透社，然后我有我的
person one of the service and I use a
人之一的服务，我用
sticky sessions and I don't know if you
粘性会议，我不知道你是否
are still using a status sticky sessions
仍在使用状态粘性会话
immediately it's really a huge problem
立即这是一个很大的问题
and basically what's happening with the
基本上发生了什么
sticky session is that it just record
粘性会话只是记录
the IP of the request and the server the
请求和服务器的IP
server who serves this request right
正确处理此请求的服务器
then if you have a shopping cart what
那如果你有购物车
you're doing is that okay the sticky
你正在做的是，好黏
session there I have the shopping cart
会议上，我有购物车
and I have the version one so all the
我有一个版本，所以所有
requests of this user always reaches
该用户的请求始终会到达
this version one service but now what's
此版本提供一项服务，但现在是什么
happened if I want to do for example a
例如，如果我想做一个
Bluegreen deployment so you've got the
蓝绿色部署，因此您已经
version one I want to change to version
我要更改为版本1
two okay now all the reroute changes to
两个好，现在所有重新路由更改都
version two and the user who had their
版本2和拥有他们的用户
own shopping cart you just seen that
您自己看到的自己的购物车
there is no shopping cart because the
没有购物车，因为
server it's not reaching any traffic how
服务器没有达到任何流量
to fix this problem basically is using
解决这个问题基本上是使用
any memory data grid and in-memory data
任何内存数据网格和内存数据
grid is a data structure that resides in
网格是驻留在其中的数据结构
Turrell in RAM and it's distributed
Turrell在RAM中并且是分布式的
among multiple services for example in
在多种服务中，例如
fin span Reddy's hazard caste all these
鳍跨Reddy的危险等级
technologies are in memory data grid and
技术在内存数据网格中
there are based in this is that for any
有根据是，对于任何
request for any version they are storing
请求他们存储的任何版本
the shopping car so this ephemeral
购物车如此短暂
estate inside this in-memory data grid
此内存数据网格内的实体
so then when you are doing for example
所以当你做例如
the blue and you switch into green
蓝色，您切换为绿色
you're getting something like this
你得到这样的东西
you've got the blue just disappear but
你有蓝色只是消失了，但是
since the green is accessing the
因为绿色正在访问
in-memory data grid and the memory data
内存数据网格和内存数据
grid is replicated across all the
网格在所有
cluster you're still getting all the
集群你仍然得到所有
shopping cart and I'm going to show you
购物车，我将向您展示
a demo if it works because I've noticed
演示是否可行，因为我注意到了
that there is some kind of problems with
有一些问题
network yeah okay now it's
网络是的，现在是
okay now I'm now I'm just starting the
好吧，现在我正在开始
cluster because I had some problem with
集群，因为我有一些问题
network is there any question meanwhile
同时网络有任何问题
start no yeah
开始没有
hello ah perfect right so my question is
你好啊，完美的权利，所以我的问题是
how would you handle migrations of the
您将如何处理
data for example the in-memory data grid
数据，例如内存中的数据网格
or even if you're connecting for example
或者即使您正在连接
the green and blue deployment if you
绿色和蓝色部署，如果您
have a data base behind that how would
有一个数据库，该如何
you upgrade your data model this is the
您升级数据模型，这是
other example I will explain all the
另一个例子，我将解释所有
steps that you need to follow you you
您需要遵循的步骤
see that there is like three steps that
看到有三个步骤
you need I mean that you create three
你需要我的意思是你创造了三个
intermediate versions of your new
新的中间版本
version you'll see then with a demo and
然后您将通过演示看到版本
explain but basically it's following the
解释，但基本上是遵循
pasta law which is like that you need to
意大利面法，您需要
accept everything and send just what
接受一切并发送什么
they requires you basically you see it
他们要求你基本上你看到了
now yet it's it's not hard look well now
现在，现在看起来不难
this is working
这正在工作
I think that this this one hope so
我认为这个这一希望如此
okay so I started the wrong
好吧，所以我开始错了
I'm going to change display yeah but
我要更改显示，但是
this is nothing
这不重要
now I have this application which this
现在我有这个应用程序
application is a movie that of store so
应用程序是存储的电影，因此
you have that I have some movies and I
你有我有一些电影，我
have two versions of the same shopping a
有两个版本的同一个购物
shopping cart is that the service who
购物车是那个服务谁
serves all the all the movies so what
提供所有的电影，所以
I'm going to do is just adding some
我要做的就是添加一些
movies to one version and then I'm going
电影到一个版本，然后我要去
to do a Bluegreen deployment to another
对另一个进行蓝绿色部署
version and you see that the shopping
版本，您会看到购物
cart is never lost and I can just go
购物车永远不会丢失，我可以走了
from version one to version two and then
从第一版到第二版，然后
again to version one and the user will
再次版本一，用户将
always have the shopping car ready so
总是准备好购物车，所以
now that it's working they can just
现在它正在工作，他们可以
this thing
这东西
okay it's just talking okay now
好吧，现在只是在说好
then what I need to do is to go to make
那我要做的就是
this work this is what I need to know
这是我需要知道的工作
that's the first thing
那是第一件事
what's not working because reddy's it's
什么是行不通的，因为reddy是
not up yet
还没有
yes where is it sup well let's see now
是的，它在哪里很好，让我们现在看看
um me let's hope that now if not they
恩，我希望现在，如果不是他们
have recorded okay the first thing that
记录好了第一件事
they need to do is just this is as you
他们需要做的就是这就是你
can see I've got here the movies b1
可以看到我有电影b1
movies with two movies gateway and
具有两个电影网关的电影和
Ready's and notice that I have like - Oh
准备好了，请注意我喜欢-哦
/ - this is because I have a pot with
-这是因为我有一个锅
two containers the service and the sto
两个容器的服务和存储
container so the first thing that I need
容器，所以我需要的第一件事
to do is send I mean that instruct
要做的就是发送，我的意思是指示
easier that there are all these services
所有这些服务更容易
they're running destination rules
他们正在运行目标规则
okay there's already a distinction route
好了，已经有一条区分路线
so this is I'm registering and then the
所以这是我正在注册，然后
other thing that they need to do is send
他们需要做的另一件事是发送
all the traffic to version B 1 which
版本B 1的所有流量
maybe I still have it there okay so now
也许我在那里还可以，所以现在
all the traffic goes to service 1 and if
所有流量都流向服务1，如果
this works
这有效
finally yeah
终于是
you see here this is the movies and one
你看这里是电影和一部
important thing is this one this is the
重要的是这是这个
host who are serving this page and
服务此页面的主持人
notice that this movies be one so I need
注意这部电影是一部，所以我需要
to buy some some films infinity Wars how
买一些电影无限战争如何
many copies - I will say - Captain
很多副本-我会说-队长
Marvel Wow
奇迹哇
zero add an item buy it ok I bite -
零添加一个项目，好吧，我咬了-
infinity Wars and I took out so if I go
无限战争，我拿出了，所以如果我去
here to the cart you see that I've added
在这里，您看到我已添加的购物车
to infinity Wars and again the host is
到无限战争，主机又是
the movies b1 so I can go again two
电影b1，所以我可以再去两部
motors and I'm going to reroute all the
电机，我将重新路由所有
traffic to version v2 the only thing
流量到版本v2唯一
that I need to is a dual replace of
我需要的是双重替代
source main still which was service veto
源主要仍然是服务否决权
so I'm just
所以我只是
we're routing the traffic from b1 to b2
我们将流量从b1路由到b2
then I can go i refresh
然后我可以去刷新
notice here now there is v2 please no v1
注意这里现在有v2，请不要v1
and the shopping car is still here with
购物车还在
one element which is the two of infinity
一个元素是无限的两个
war and I can go back here and I can buy
战争，我可以回到这里，我可以购买
this one which my daughter will be
这是我女儿会的
really happy and of course I have here
真的很高兴，我当然在这里
both of the movies and if I detect that
两部电影，如果我检测到
there is some error in v2 and I want to
v2中存在一些错误，我想
get back to be one I just need to go
回到一个我只需要走的地方
here apply this file and now when I just
在这里应用这个文件，现在当我只是
refresh you see the here is the p1 again
刷新，您会再次看到这里是p1
and the movies where the movies but
和电影，但电影
there is the link here you see that
这里有链接，您会看到
there is the how to train your dragon an
有如何训练你的龙
Avengers so I'm not losing the state
复仇者联盟，所以我不会失去状态
anymore and can just switch all the time
而且可以随时切换
from version one to version two without
从第一版到第二版，没有
much problem
很大的问题
then next example it's the one that you
那么下一个例子就是你
mention about what's happening when
提及何时发生的事情
there is persistence what's happening
有持续性发生了什么
because now it's really easy right you
因为现在真的很容易
have the red is there you're just
有红色就在那里
sending and and see what's happened to
发送并查看发生了什么
make this I'm going to first of all
首先，我要
explain you one thing so what's happened
向你解释一件事，所以发生了什么事
when we have a persistent state when we
当我们有一个持久的状态时
have the database basically I'm going to
基本上我有数据库
explain you the most complex example
向您解释最复杂的例子
with this example then you can you know
通过这个例子，那么你可以知道
take the idea and turn apply it to any
接受这个想法并将其应用于任何
other transform that happens on a
发生在
database under this one is that and
在这个数据库下是
update the column name for example
例如更新列名
you've got the column name name and you
你有列名name而你
want to rename it to full name
想要重命名为全名
I've got version 1 with the data way
我有版本1的数据方式
with a race with a column called name
比赛中有一个叫名字的列
then I want to rename this column to
然后我想将此列重命名为
full name so it's happen if I do for
全名，所以如果我为
example can you release it means that
你可以释放它的例子意味着
some if the column name does not change
如果列名不变则一些
it's not a problem but if the column
这不是问题，但如果专栏
name change then some users might find
更改名称，然后一些用户可能会发现
some problems right because one column
有些问题是因为一列
is called full name because you rename
之所以称为全名，是因为您重命名
it the column and then one percent of
它列，然后百分之一
the users will get it the correct
用户会得到正确的
response but 99% of the users will
回应，但99％的使用者会
receive column name not found so how to
收到未找到的列名，那么如何
do it the first thing that you need to
要做第一件事
do is do do something like this you've
做就是做你这样的事情
got version 1 that needs to read and
有版本1需要阅读并
write to name and full name so you are
写姓名和全名，这样你就可以
duplicating the fields any red kinetic
复制领域任何红色动力学
right of version 1 should go to both of
版本1的权利应同时应用于
these columns and the version 2 just
这些专栏和版本2只是
read from the the full name
从全名中读取
notice that in this way but your what
注意这种方式，但是你的
you are getting is that if there is
你得到的是，如果有
version two behaving incorrectly you can
版本二行为不正确，您可以
always get back without losing anything
总是回来而不会丢失任何东西
and of course if there is a bright
当然如果有明亮的
because at the end the users will read
因为最终用户将阅读
something they cried to both full name
他们哭了两个全名
and name the reason of this is that if
并指出其原因是，如果
version 2 you need to roll back it to
版本2，您需要将其回滚到
version p1 the all the data is a still a
版本p1的所有数据仍然是
name although your you know final step
命名，尽管您知道最后一步
is just having full name this is for the
只是全名而已
first time then remember that we've got
第一次，然后记住，我们已经
version 2 having the right to name them
版本2有权为其命名
full name and birth and ready and
全名和出生，并准备好
reading from name but you want to end up
从名字读，但你想结束
by removing name so the first thing that
通过删除名称，第一件事就是
you need to do with version 3 is just
您需要使用版本3只是
something like that
这样的东西
I copy all the previous data from name
我从名称复制所有先前的数据
to full name
全名
because remember that you have added for
因为请记住您已经添加了
him at the middle of I mean that your
他在我中间的意思是你
valid maybe after one year of running
可能在运行一年后才有效
this application so you need to copy the
此应用程序，因此您需要复制
previous data from name to full name and
从名称到全名的先前数据，以及
probably will use something like a
可能会使用类似
spring batch to batch all this
Spring 批处理所有这一切
information from column to column so you
列与列之间的信息使您
don't lock the full database after that
之后不要锁定整个数据库
you this version 3 will start reading
您这个版本3将开始阅读
all the information from full name since
自全名以来的所有信息
you have copied everything from name to
您已将所有内容从名称复制到
full name then you have not lost
全名，那么您还没有丢失
anything
任何东西
and the write still happened to name and
并且写仍然碰巧命名和
full name and you need to do it in this
全名，您需要这样做
way again for the same reason if version
同样的原因，如果版本
3 has any error and you need to row back
3有任何错误，您需要回退
you still need to be able to work with
您仍然需要能够与
version 2 and if you see version 2 the
版本2，如果您看到版本2，
rate is happening from column name so
速率是从列名发生的，所以
you still need to write the column name
您仍然需要写列名
and the last thing that you need to do
还有你要做的最后一件事
is like I have now version 3 which
就像我现在有版本3
writes to bottom rate from full name
从全名写入最低费用
what I need to do is just a start
我需要做的只是一个开始
read and write from full name so after 3
以全名读取和写入，因此在3之后
steps your application has me
您的申请有我的步骤
rated from reading from column name to
从列名读取到
reading and writing to full name so you
阅读和写全名，这样你
need to read in these three steps if you
如果您需要阅读这三个步骤
don't do it in that way I know that it's
不要那样做，我知道这是
somehow complex but if you don't do it
有点复杂，但是如果你不这样做
that way it's impossible to guarantee a
这样就不可能保证
backward compatibility with zero zone
向后兼容零区
time of course you can do you can try
当然可以，您可以尝试
zero a long time and see what's
零了很久，看看是什么
happening and with out zero home time
发生并且没有零时间
just to stop everything star everything
只是为了阻止一切星光一切
and see what's heaven but if you want to
看看天堂是什么，但是如果你想
do it with live code you need to eat
用您需要吃的实时代码完成
following all these steps so let's see
遵循所有这些步骤，让我们看看
now this example I've got here
现在这个例子我在这里
I'm just this is Cuban artists cluster
我就是古巴艺术家
when it's openshift but at the end up
当它是openshift但最终
achieve its Cuban it is you see that I'm
实现它的古巴，那是你看到我
going to use cube City all the time and
将一直使用多维数据集城市，并且
this is okay now I've got next well we
没关系，现在我有下一个井
can wait let me open so it will be easy
可以等我打开，这很容易
and if you see again this k9 I've got a
如果您再次看到这个k9，我有一个
customer I have a preference be one I
我最喜欢的客户是我
have recommendation before I mean that
在我的意思之前有建议
because b1 b2 me three it's for all the
因为b1 b2我是三个
things and now before it's like the
事情，现在才像
standard standard version like that the
像这样的标准标准版本
big one from normal way and I have here
从正常的方式大，我在这里
the Postgres and if you check what this
Postgres，如果您检查这是什么
cause of Postgres contains I can do P
Postgres的原因包含我可以执行P
Square
广场
and you can see they have an ID and a
您会看到他们有一个ID和一个
name the name is Star Wars a new hope
名字叫星球大战一个新希望
and a Star Trek v contact this is just
和星际迷航v联络这只是
the name and I want to rename this name
这个名字，我想重命名这个名字
to another thing of course they will do
他们当然会做另一件事
here a call you see them getting I'm
在这里打个电话，你看到他们越来越我
getting customer preference
获得客户的偏爱
recommendation before Star Wars a new
星球大战之前的推荐新
home Star Trek this contract now what's
星际迷航》这本合同现在是什么
happen if I want to add for example a
如果我想添加一个例子
new movie I just need to do a call means
新电影，我只需要打电话即可
H I'm going to add for example avengers'
H我要添加例如复仇者
now we've added a new movie to the old
现在我们在旧电影中添加了新电影
version so of course they do the Select
版本，所以他们当然会选择
you see that there is this movie as well
您会看到也有这部电影
and have to hear the call then I've got
而且必须听到电话，然后我得到了
Star Trek Star Wars and Avengers now I
《星际迷航》《星际大战》和《复仇者联盟》现在我
want to deploy a version b5 which is you
想要部署b5版本
know the start of the rename the only
知道重命名的开始唯一
thing that I need to do I'm going to do
我需要做的事情
it from here excuse it yell applying and
从这里请原谅它大声申请，
the deployment that I'm going to use is
我要使用的部署是
notice that what I'm doing here is just
注意，我在这里所做的只是
taking deployment b5 which is my normal
进行b5部署，这是我的常规
deployment and I'm just passing through
部署，我正在经历
cubing Jack which modifies this Jamel
修改杰米的杰克
file to add all these Easter magic and
文件来添加所有这些复活节魔术和
no because okay okay now I'm just
不，因为好吧，好吧，我只是
deploying the next version which is
部署下一个版本
almost running remember that this new
快要跑了，记得这个新
version which is doing just creating the
版本只是在创建
column name and this new version is
列名称，此新版本是
reading from the old one
读旧书
but writing to both now it's running
但是现在写到两者都在运行
anybody here a select this see that
任何人在这里选择这个看到
there is a movie named failed there's a
有一部名为失败的电影，有一部
new field right and all field I want to
新字段的权利以及我想要的所有字段
rename from name to movie name then
然后从名称重命名为电影名称
again what I need to do is reroute the
再次，我需要做的是重新路由
traffic to this b5 to reroute the
流量到此b5以重新路由
traffic to be file just need to do is to
只需要做的流量就是
city replace new self-service b5 now I'm
我现在要更换新的自助服务b5
just sending all the traffic to the p5
只是将所有流量发送到p5
version and if it to a call not is that
版本，如果不是，则为
I'm getting recommendation b5 with the
我得到的建议b5与
three movies what's happened if I do now
三部电影，如果我现在去做什么
a call and for example I yet another
一个电话，例如我又一个
movie for example frozen would be a good
例如电影冻结将是一个很好的
movie now that they are going to release
电影，他们将要发行
frozen those which going to put frozen
冻结那些将要冻结的
one
一
now let's have anybody work here a
现在让任何人在这里工作
select you are seeing that frozen are
选择您正在看到冻结的
added to both columns and of course I
添加到两列，当然我
can do here the curve which is Star Trek
可以在这里做是星际迷航的曲线
infinity and frozen if I notice that oh
如果我注意到那无限和冻结哦
now there is an error in this version b5
现在此版本b5中存在错误
I need to switch back to before I can
我需要先切换回
just do is to sit yeah replace my new
只是要做的就是坐，取代我的新
self is two files
自我是两个文件
Piero's service b5 I saw before now I do
我之前看到的Piero的服务b5
a curl and of course now it's before but
卷发，当然现在是
the frozen movie it's still there so
冰冻的电影，它仍然在那里
notice that the version before didn't
注意之前的版本没有
know anything about movie name field
对电影名称字段一无所知
because there was not created yet but
因为还没有创建，但是
since I've read it to both of the places
因为我在两个地方都读过
then I get it
然后我明白了
the data in both then let's suppose that
然后假设两者中的数据
everything works as expected and the b5
一切正常，b5
it's correct so I can just pop back to
是正确的，所以我可以跳回到
b5 and I deploy the next step to this
b5和我将下一步部署到此
emigration which is deploying the b6 so
正在部署b6的移民
I just need to go do a keep CTL apply of
我只需要继续应用CTL
deployment b6 well first of all to not
部署b6首先要做好
get crazy I'm going to do a version
疯了，我要去做一个版本
before so now since b5 it's good then I
以前是现在，因为b5很好，然后我
can just um deploy before and I'm going
可以在之前部署，而我要去
to redeploy b6 so now I've got b5 and
重新部署b6，所以现在我有了b5，
then you have b6 and when I have
那么你有b6，当我有
[Music]
[音乐]
starting basically now with the b6 what
现在基本上从b6开始
I'm doing is copying from the old data
我正在做的是从旧数据复制
to the new I mean from the old column to
到新的意思是从旧列到
the new column and now regionright
新列，现在是regionright
happens in the new
发生在新的
columns let's see okay now it's
专栏让我们看看现在好了
everything running and I've do a select
一切都在运行，我已经做了一个选择
here you see but now the Star Wars or
在这里您会看到，但现在是《星球大战》或
start sneaking Avengers that came from
开始潜入来自的复仇者联盟
before are copied to movie names notice
之前复制到电影名称的通知
that in the previous select these
在前面选择这些
elements were not there but now they are
元素不在那里，但现在它们在
there so again I can just do one mystery
在那里，我可以再做一个谜
city I'll replace just your files
城市，我将只替换您的文件
withdrawal service v6 and I can do a
提款服务v6，我可以
call and I'm getting all the movies from
打电话给我看所有电影
b6 again if I can just switch back to I
b6如果我可以切换回我的话
can I mean that if you wanna can do a
我的意思是，如果您想做一个
crawl adding some data for example now
例如现在抓取添加一些数据
let's add any movie okay Toy Story for
让我们为它添加任何电影“玩具总动员”
and of course I can do a curl and then
我当然可以卷发，然后
put a storage here and again I can if I
如果我可以的话，可以一次又一次地存储
detect any error I can switch back to
检测到我可以切换回的任何错误
the number five and I can do a call and
五号，我可以打个电话，
of course Toy Story 4 it's still there
当然，《玩具总动员4》仍然存在
the final step will be just to delete p5
最后一步就是删除p5
well not because I'm still the rolls
好吧，不是因为我仍然卷
pointing out to be 6j I'm going to screw
指出我要拧6j
em boy replace to b6 and then I can
em boy替换为b6，然后我可以
leave b5 and finally I can just deploy
离开b5，最后我可以部署
the last one which is v7 which is
最后一个是v7
another version which now I'm just
现在我只是另一个版本
changing where the data is written right
更改正确写入数据的位置
now the reason right are happening from
现在的原因是正确的
the all and from the new columns so in
全部，并来自新列
terms of new columns its happen nothing
新列的条款没有任何反应
but what's happened now if I do this
但是如果我这样做现在会发生什么
I'm going to change this to be seven of
我将其更改为七个
course the call still returns to be
当然，通话仍然返回
seven but if I add a new then I don't
七个，但是如果我添加一个新的，我不会
know exactly what I have here another
确切地知道我在这里还有另一个
one
一
any movie what sure Terminator the one I
任何电影都可以确定终结者
mean that the original one yeah because
意思是原来的是的，因为
now there is a lot of Terminator all
现在有很多终结者
right okay do the call but now notice
好吧，打个电话，但现在注意
that if I do a select Terminator is just
如果我选择“终结者”
in the new column not in the old one and
在新列中而不是旧列中
you said and this is going to work if I
你说的，如果我这样，这将起作用
do a robot to the version sees of course
当然要对版本做一个机器人
because version six you just get it from
因为第六版只是从
the new one so you can just replace I go
新的，所以你可以取代我去
back to six
回到六
I do the call and what Terminator is
我打了电话，终结者是什么
there so I'm just you know doing all
在那里，我只是你知道所有事情
these three versions always back
这三个版本总是回来
compatibility we've seen that I've been
兼容性，我们已经看到我一直
switching from the old and the new and
从新旧转换
adding data and the data is never lost
添加数据，数据永不丢失
so we're almost done
所以我们快完成了
if you I mean that if you want to check
如果你的意思是如果你想检查
all these examples and go deep in inside
所有这些例子，深入了解
sto you can go to this is tutorial which
sto，你可以去这是教程
is everything is explained and this also
一切都在解释，这也是
teach it in case that you want to you
如果你想教你
have some knowledge of Eastern you just
对东方人有一些了解
want a summary of everything one of the
想要其中的所有内容的摘要
things that you might find is that
你可能会发现的是
what's happened when I'm mirroring
我正在镜像时发生了什么
traffic right what's happening back
正确的交通回头
sending the request to two services of
发送请求到两个服务
two different versions and there is an
两种不同的版本，
insert that I'm doing to insert to the
我正在插入的插入
same database right to avoid this you
同样的数据库权限可以避免这种情况
can use two approaches but there are
可以使用两种方法，但是有
actually three but I will explain you
实际上是三个，但我会向您解释
two the first one is using synthetic
两个第一个是使用合成
drug sanctions in turning transactions
交易中的毒品制裁
is just detecting that the traffic is
只是检测到流量
shallow with traffic which is really
流量很浅
easy with this do and then just roll
这样做很容易，然后滚动
back all the transactions so you receive
支持所有交易，以便您收到
two inserts to service BB one and
两个插入件以服务BB一和
service VB to there are sending two
服务VB到那里有发送两个
inserts to the database right but when
正确插入数据库，但是当
the reader which responds to the v2 then
然后对v2做出响应的阅读器
there is a row back so this insert never
后面有一排，所以此插入永远不会
happens inside the database
发生在数据库内部
another option is just create a
另一个选择就是创建一个
beautiful orb utilize the database
漂亮的球利用数据库
cluster so you've got something like
集群，所以你有类似
this what the production database and
这是什么生产数据库和
then I have a bill to all database for
然后我有一张账单到所有数据库
example using Kate which is an
使用凯特的例子
open-source tool and then all the rates
开源工具，然后是所有费率
happens from production and all the
发生在生产和所有
rights goes to a throwaway database so
权利进入了一次性数据库，因此
you're just shallow in the traffic to
您的交通流量很浅
both of the of the services the inserts
两种服务的插入
goes to this throwaway and then when you
去这个一次性的东西，然后当你
switch from v1 to v2 then you just need
从v1切换到v2，那么您只需要
to remove all these throwaway database
删除所有这些一次性数据库
we're almost done well I mean that it's
我们几乎做得很好，我的意思是
you know somehow difficult
你知道很难
let's end this way to maintain a zero
让我们以这种方式结束保持零
downtime deployment with micro services
使用微服务进行停机部署
but just you know forget about what
但只有你知道忘记什么
you've done in the past and just start
您过去已经做过，只是开始
applying these new techniques with
将这些新技术应用于
history which is really easy to do as
历史，这真的很容易做到
you've seen proceed with caution
您已经看到谨慎行事
because remember that there is an O in
因为记住在里面有一个O
the case of a renaming a column there is
在重命名列的情况下
a still a column there with all the data
还有所有数据的一列
and probably no sequel administration
而且可能没有续集管理
administrator will allow you to delete
管理员将允许您删除
this column but and theory the last step
本专栏，但理论上的最后一步
should be delete the old column and well
应该删除旧列
I mean that there is also this kind of
我的意思是也有这种
books with some of these conflicts I'll
有一些冲突的书，我会
explain it but it basically this one
解释一下，但基本上这是一个
which is berating two microservice e
指责两个微服务e
databases from eighteen Janaka explained
Janaka的18个数据库进行了解释
this technique and other use cases and
这种技术和其他用例，以及
they you can download it for free from
他们可以从以下位置免费下载
developers address that come you just go
开发人员地址，您随便走
there you register and then you can
在那儿注册，然后就可以
download at all of them and that's all
全部下载，仅此而已
if there is any question just can form
如果有任何问题就可以形成
in Twitter or even send me an email I
在Twitter上，甚至给我发送电子邮件
mean that some people ask me can I send
意味着有人问我可以发送
you an email and yeah you can send in
您会收到一封电子邮件，是的，您可以发送
email because it's here the mail if not
电子邮件，因为如果不是，这里是邮件
it will mean over here thank you
这意味着在这里谢谢
you
您
[Applause]
[掌声]
[Music]
[音乐]